<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description></description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 15:01:03 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2016 15:01:03 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Avoid Vacation Scheduling Headaches - 3 Ways to Stay Ahead of the Problem</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s face it—we all need a break. If you haven’t added some time off to your own calendar, you may want to take a few minutes to pencil some in. Go ahead. I’ll wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel better? I thought so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/3-TIPS-ON-AVOIDING-VACATION-SCHEDULING-HEADACHES.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Avoid Vacation Scheduling Headaches&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’ve set aside some vacation time for yourself, it’s time to consider your employees. If they haven’t requested any time off yet, you know it’s coming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summer is prime-time for vacations which, while important for employee morale (and everyone’s sanity), can be a big headache for managers trying to balance multiple vacations requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you stay ahead of the problem, and keep yourself from tearing your hair out every summer? Here are three steps you can take to stay cool and keep the office happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan ahead.&lt;/strong&gt; Every &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/nimblenews/blog/staff-management-tips/&quot;&gt;staff management&lt;/a&gt; plan should have clear vacation policies. While your employees may already have a set number of days off and a set period of time in which they must notify you prior to taking time off—you may need to add a few vacation planning guidelines to your employee scheduling policy during busy vacation times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a season that’s historically difficult when it comes to vacation scheduling, let your staff know in advance when they need to have their requests in by. If you have all your requests in advance, it’ll be much easier for you to plan accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget to be clear about your policy either. No one wants their summer plans ruined because they didn’t understand the vacation planning policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Involve your employees.&lt;/strong&gt; Nothing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/nimblenews/blog/increase-employee-engagement/&quot;&gt;keeps employees engaged&lt;/a&gt; quite like getting involved in a decision making process. So, while you’re planning ahead and clarifying the vacation planning policy, open a line of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/communicate-instantly/&quot;&gt;communication with your staff&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are any of them planning a summer vacation? When are they thinking about going, and for how long?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Involving your employees allows you to plan ahead and engage with them on a more personal level at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communicate clearly.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’ve already planned ahead and brought your employees into the conversation, the most important thing for you to do now is to keep the communication channels open through the vacation season.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know you’ll be a little light on staff for a few weeks, make sure that the staff members who will be out communicate any important functions that need to be picked up with those still in the office. Also, make sure you’re up to date on what your staff is working on in case you need to pick up any slack or direct someone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget to stay positive through the vacation planning process. While vacation scheduling can be a headache for you, your staff will appreciate the break. Keep yourself sane by remembering to plan ahead, keep staff involved, and keep the communication lines open.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 12:30:24 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/avoid-vacation-scheduling-headaches-3-ways-to-stay-ahead-of-the-problem/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/avoid-vacation-scheduling-headaches-3-ways-to-stay-ahead-of-the-problem/</guid>
        
        <category>Vacation Time</category>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>4 Things You Can Do to Keep Employees Engaged Through the Summer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Remember summers as a kid?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nine long months of school culminating in three months of total freedom. No homework to worry about. No dress code. No teachers. And best of all, you probably had nothing to do all day but ride your bike and play with your friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many of us, those were good times. Unfortunately, a three-month long summer vacation isn’t a perk that most of us get to take with us into adulthood.
Summer hasn’t lost its luster, though. Many working adults—especially those with kids—still associate summer with freedom and vacations. It’s no surprise that employee engagement and workplace productivity &lt;a href=&quot;http://officepulse.captivate.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/Captivate-Summer-Hours-Release-Final.pdf&quot;&gt;drops by about 20%&lt;/a&gt; during the summer months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you keep employees productive and engaged as the days get longer and the temperatures rise?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/employee-engagement-during-the-summer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;4 Things You Can Do Right Now to Keep Employees Engaged Through the Summer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few things you can do right now to improve performance management and keep employees engaged at a time that’s often less productive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep the communication channels open.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/nimblenews/product-news/tips-tricks/employee-communication-tools/&quot;&gt;Good communication&lt;/a&gt; is—or should be—a foundational element in any workplace. While some of your employees may be in and out of the office with vacation, it’s important to stay in touch and keep your relationship with workers alive and well.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Encourage vacation.&lt;/strong&gt; Do you have a vacation planned? Don’t forget that your employees need one, too. While they may be trying to focus on that big project you’ve assigned, it’s still important to take a break.
Don’t let your employees turn into zombies by working all year without a vacation. Encourage your staff to take time off appropriately, rather than costing your organization time and money with low productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/nimblenews/blog/team-building-tips/&quot;&gt;team building&lt;/a&gt; activities.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re not doing this already, planning and organizing team building exercises can go a long way toward boosting employee morale. 
There are lots of ways you could approach this, and some activities will be better suited to some workplaces than others. If you haven’t tried any team building activities, just try doing something around the office like a lunchtime potluck. Another great option is taking an afternoon to volunteer somewhere locally as a group.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be flexible with staff scheduling.&lt;/strong&gt; Some of your employees may already have requested time off during the summer, but you know there’ll be some last minute requests. While you certainly want to be sensitive to your own bottom-line, the negative effects of low employee morale may take a higher toll on your organization than granting a last minute time off request.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know about you, but I’d rather not sit inside all summer. Your employees probably don’t want to either. So, plan ahead, loosen up the office a bit, and take advantage of the extra sunshine to boost your employee morale.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 14:30:28 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/boosting-employee-engagement-through-the-summer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/boosting-employee-engagement-through-the-summer/</guid>
        
        <category>Employee Engagement</category>
        
        <category>Employee Morale</category>
        
        <category>Performance Management</category>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can Poor Customer Service Get Your Business In Trouble?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Listening to compliments about your company’s customer service certainly feels nice. A pat on the back after a hard working day spent with the existing or new clients is always much appreciated. However, do not be fooled; good customer service doesn’t lead to just a couple of nice compliments that will make you feel good. There’s so much more to it than that. On the other hand, poor and underperforming customer service may significantly impair your business in many different ways. In this article, we’ll cover some of the most harmful effects of poor customer service and consequences it can produce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/inferior-customer-support.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Good Customer Service&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;customer-retention&quot;&gt;Customer Retention&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Underperforming customer support can lead to serious client retention issues. Poor service will most likely cost your business some existing clients, who will just cancel the service after receiving the customer support they expected. In other words, a higher churn rate will lead your business to lower income, thus ultimately causing the shutdown of your company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;prospect-loss&quot;&gt;Prospect loss&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A large percentage of prospects decides to just cancel their purchase or subscription to a product or service due to poor initial customer service. Even though they actually do need a service or a product offered, and they originally intended to buy it, any sort of poor customer service, or simply a lack of support may cause them to second-guess their intention to subscribe or purchase your goods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;reputation-damage-and-loss&quot;&gt;Reputation damage and loss&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are proponents of the idea that sometimes even bad publicity can be better than none at all. Well, perhaps it’s time to re-consider that assertation if you are one of those people. A bad experience with customer support will lead to negative comments and bad &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/nimblenews/blog/the-word-of-mouth/&quot;&gt;word of mouth&lt;/a&gt;, which will not just cause you to lose some future clients you could have gained by providing good customer service, but it may also significantly affect your business’ reputation and negatively impact your company in terms of not getting more clients, not being able to hire good employees, and similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;higher-employee-turnover&quot;&gt;Higher employee turnover&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, no one wants to be yelled at or deal with angry clients all the time. If the provided customer service is not up to par and causes a considerable number of clients to be unhappy, that trend may cause a higher employee turnover as well. In other words, it  may become significantly harder to hire some of those &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/nimblenews/blog/3-secrets-to-finding-great-employees/&quot;&gt;great employees&lt;/a&gt; that you keep hearing about from your friends or colleagues managing other companies. The cost of hiring and training new employees may get your business into financial trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;rectifying-is-sometimes-hard&quot;&gt;Rectifying is sometimes hard&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making things right after a bad customer support experience is quite challenging. Your customer support team needs to make a dozen, if not more, positive impressions to make it up for one lousy impression they left on a client. And even if the manager gives the client a call to apologize or tries to rectify a bad experience, the bad taste will remain and make the client be extra careful in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;loss-of-profit&quot;&gt;Loss of profit&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, it’s needless to say that all the previously listed things eventually lead to a loss of profit and may often times significantly hurt your business. It is because of that reason we suggest spending more time on recruiting a good customer support team and training them properly; otherwise, you might suffer some of these consequences later on. The fact that not all of the clients will immediately complain about the poor service they received is an extra reason to implement right policies regardless of the feedback you get on a daily basis. Being extra careful can’t hurt anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2016 14:05:56 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/can-poor-customer-service-get-your-business-in-trouble/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/can-poor-customer-service-get-your-business-in-trouble/</guid>
        
        <category>Customer Experience</category>
        
        <category>Customer Satisfaction</category>
        
        <category>Customer Service</category>
        
        <category>Customer Support</category>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Secrets to Finding Great Employees</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Your employees are (or should be) your most valued asset. They are your brand’s face to your customers and they can make you or break you. But how do you find super star employees? Here are my 3 secrets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask Current Employees&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s said that we tend to “keep like company” so one of the best ways to find great employees is to talk to your &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/nimblenews/blog/ideal-employees-among-us/&quot;&gt;current great employees&lt;/a&gt;. Let them know that you’re looking for a new hire. Ask them if they have friends that would make great employees. Honest hard-working people tend to have friends with similar traits so your current employees can be a great source for prospective employees. You can even incentivize your employees to help you find good people. Offer them a cash reward for every new hire that stays. It doesn’t have to be extravagant, even something simple like a gas card shows your employees that you value their help in finding the right people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask Around&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ask your friends and family if they know anyone that would be a good fit. Presumably, they’ll want to help and will help you find good people. Never assume that your friends know that you need people just because you have a job posting on LinkedIn or a ‘Now Hiring’ sign in your window. Go out of your way to ask them. Let them know exactly who you’re looking for. If they don’t know of someone, they can always keep their eyes open for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/In-Hiring-a-Friend-in-Need-Is-a-Prospect-Indeed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Hire - Secrets to Finding Great Employees &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep Your Eyes Peeled&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You never know where you’re going to find your next super star. It may be in the most unlikely of places, so keep your eyes open as you go through your day. If you receive exceptional service at one of the places you frequent, take note of that and ask the person if they are interested in applying for a position. You may even want to hire your Uber driver (I found a great intern that way)! Using websites like LinkedIn and asking connections for referrals is a great way to find a great employee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build vs. Buy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiring employees is expensive. There is a cost for recruiting. Time and expense of training. So, whenever possible, leverage your investment. One of your best, potential places for finding your next great employees is by growing and grooming one of your current “good” employees. If someone shows good initiative, cares and works hard, do what you can to cultivate them as an employee. Train them. Teach them. Groom them.  Show them that you value them. Reward them when they do well. And that doesn’t necessarily mean money. You can give them special scheduling accommodation, or give them a holiday or birthday off. The more an employee feels valued, the more likely they are to strive to do more. 
Your employees are your life blood. It’s hard to find truly great workers, and in order to do so, you may have to think outside the box a bit. Once you find them, do everything you can to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/nimblenews/blog/5-secrets-to-keep-your-best-employees/&quot;&gt;keep them&lt;/a&gt;.  Whether you find them, grow them, or take them from your competitors, you need to invest in them and challenge them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your tips for finding great employees? We’d love to hear from you!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 12:46:52 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/3-secrets-to-finding-great-employees/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/3-secrets-to-finding-great-employees/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Rely on Fate - Get Technology to Help Your Startup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world of self-driving cars and virtual reality technology, there are no excuses for still using a corkboard as your primary way of planning and organizing your business. There are so many other ways in which you can apply the latest technology, cloud-based or not, to help your business thrive. A variety of tools and systems being widely used nowadays makes this process simple and smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On one hand, the latest technologies can help you manage your staffing procedures with less headaches. Numerous cloud platforms available on the market allow you to easily seek for, hire and manage your workforce. From a myriad of HR platforms available, to cloud-based payroll systems, and all kinds of staff scheduling, time tracking, project and workforce management systems, innovative cloud technologies streamline the business management of organizations in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Cut-that-Excel-sheet-in-half.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Workforce Management&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the latest technologies can simplify the way you track your clients and improve communication with them, as well as  collect valuable feedback and ratings from them. Unless you’ve made a decision to run your business by blindly guessing what your clients think about your existing operations, or what their exact needs are, then such platforms can radically help you improve your product or service by collecting valuable information and communicating effectively with your customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll cover some of the technologies you can put in place to do the job for you and help you manage various aspects of your business related primarily to staff management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;employee-management&quot;&gt;Employee Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;hr&quot;&gt;HR&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Modern HR platforms available on the market today allow you to easily onboard new staff members and even automate their training process. Gathering required paperwork in a digital form is a part of all the modern &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/nimblenews/blog/perks-of-cloud-hr-management-technology/&quot;&gt;HR platforms&lt;/a&gt; in the market. You can freely say ‘Goodbye’ to all the paperwork stored around your offices and host everything safely in the cloud. Managing your employees’ PTO and accrual records is also a piece of cake with cloud-based HR systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;scheduling&quot;&gt;Scheduling&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Storing your staff’s schedule on various excel spreadsheet files or, god forbid, on a bulletin board in your corporate hallway is part of the past. The robustness of cloud-based &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/&quot;&gt;staff scheduling&lt;/a&gt; apps allows you to easily manage any kind of scheduling needs, while automatically checking for any kind of shift or time off related conflicts. Such platforms simply allow you to cut down on time needed to dedicate to the scheduling process and focus your time and efforts on more valuable aspects of your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tasks-and-projects&quot;&gt;Tasks and Projects&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rich online task and project management platforms allow your team members to stay on track with various projects being done around the same time. While such systems allow your employees to easily access all the data needed for specific projects or assignments, at any time of the day or night, or stay in the loop with collaborative progress and updates, they also ensure efficient team management in order to help your team focus their efforts in terms of meeting deadlines and completing their assignments and tasks. From software projects to any other kind of planning and organizing, cloud-based project management platforms are a must for any larger organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;time-tracking&quot;&gt;Time Tracking&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud-based technology enables company owners and managers to effectively and accurately track their workforce attendance. In order to help various businesses stay on top of all sorts of compliances, modern cloud-based time tracking software can display employees’ effective work time at any time of the day, accurate down to the number of seconds monitored. With such a technology on hand, you can finally stop dealing with complicated time card systems or half-manual processes, and start utilizing cloud-based time tracking systems to do the work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;payroll&quot;&gt;Payroll&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Executing payroll on time, and delivering your staff’s wages to their bank accounts on time is a big thing in any organization. Delays in cutting paychecks can cause unnecessary distractions from the work focus and goals, not to mention unpleasant conversations and mumbles in your company hallways. With a variety of cloud-based payroll systems, there’s just no excuse not to put one of them into work. Furthermore, these platforms will even help you to easily manage various policies and regulations, such as overtime, and similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is your favorite cloud-based software and how well does it help you run your startup?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 12:30:21 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/dont-rely-on-fate-get-technology-to-help-your-startup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/dont-rely-on-fate-get-technology-to-help-your-startup/</guid>
        
        <category>Staff Management</category>
        
        <category>Time Tracking Software</category>
        
        <category>Workforce Management</category>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Secrets to Keep Your Best Employees</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Employee turnover isn’t just expensive; it can jeopardize your entire organization’s operations. So how do you keep your best and brightest from walking out the door? There are a lot of little things that you can do to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/nimblenews/blog/keep-employees-happy/&quot;&gt;keep your employees happy&lt;/a&gt;. Here are a few secrets to add to your arsenal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;be-accommodating&quot;&gt;Be Accommodating&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Treat your employees how you’d like to be treated. Show them that you care by trying to be accommodating to their needs. In the 1920s, Henry Ford implemented an employee well-being program, one of the first of its kind. He expected his front-line managers to know how their employees were doing. Were they having difficulty at home? Were their children sick? The intention of this program was not to pry into their lives but to understand how the managers could support their workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Always-treat-your-employees-exactly-as-you-want-them-to-treat-your-best-customers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;5 Secrets to Reduce Employee Turnover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to be accommodating when employees ask for special considerations such as days off and vacations. Try to go the extra mile by remembering and acknowledging birthdays, work and wedding anniversaries. Just remembering these dates will help your employees to know that you care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;show-respect&quot;&gt;Show Respect&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showing your employees that you trust, respect and value their opinions and contributions to to the organization is key. Whenever possible ask your employees for their input and opinion. An employee who feels their opinion is valued is far more likely to stay with their employer. Remember your employees are your company’s “face to the customer” and, as such, they can provide you with valuable insights about what customers want and need. They can provide valuable input on how you can improve operationally. If an employee does provide you with valuable insights and suggestions, acknowledge it and if possible reward it. You’d be surprised how a little gesture like a gift card from the local coffee shop can mean to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;dont-let-them-down&quot;&gt;Don’t Let Them Down&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one may seem intuitive and seem like common sense, but you’d be surprised how often employers let down their employees. It’s critically important that you keep your word to your people. If you say you’re going to do something, you should do everything within your power to fulfill that promise. Try not to blame your employees. There are times when you will be forced to “take sides” in a dispute with a customer. However expedient it may seem to do so, never shove your employees under the bus. Even when dealing with sub-par employees, you have to avoid the temptation to blame because, if your best employees see your failure to show loyalty to others, they will always wonder if you “have their back”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The saying “the customer is always right” is a fallacy. Sometimes the customer is dead wrong, so don’t use this platitude on your employees. It insults their intelligence. The customer is not always right, but the customer is your organization’s raison d’etre so they deserve respect, so do your employees (especially so with your best employees).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;invest-in-your-employees&quot;&gt;Invest in Your Employees&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one may not be a “secret” but it always bears repeating. To your customer’s, your employees are your brand. As such, you need to value them like you value your business. Pay them what they are worth. Make an investment in them. This doesn’t always have to mean money. You can invest time to mentor, train and educate them. Teach them new skills. Cultivate their interests. Of course, you can only do this if you’ve taken the time to know what their interests are. Take the time to understand their career aspirations. As their employer, you’re in a unique position to help them fulfill their career goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-they-leave-matters&quot;&gt;How They Leave Matters&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to earn the respect and trust of your best employees is by showing respect to former employers. Losing an employee is painful, especially when they are a good employee that you’ve invested a lot of time and attention in, but how you treat them as they leave reflects on you as an employer. As hard as it may be to see them go, you should always take the high road. Wish them well. If they’ve been a good employee, let them know they are welcome to come back. If they’re a subpar employee, let them know that you’re sorry it didn’t work out and wish them well. Offer them help if they need it. Remember, every former employee is a potential brand ambassador. Leave them with a great feeling about your brand so that they tell others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employee turnover can be expensive and it can adversely impact your operations, but there are a number of small things that you can do to help retain your best employees. Some of the items I’ve mentioned are common sense, but sometimes the secret to success is exercising good, common sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your thoughts? What are your secrets to keeping your best employees?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 09:00:42 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/5-secrets-to-keep-your-best-employees/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/5-secrets-to-keep-your-best-employees/</guid>
        
        <category>Employee Retention</category>
        
        <category>employee turnover</category>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Impact of Employee Engagement on Business Performance</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the crucial components of success when running a business is having highly engaged employees. Naturally, that’s not the only important thing in the business equation, but it certainly is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gallup.com/businessjournal/163130/employee-engagement-drives-growth.aspx&quot;&gt;a distinguishing factor&lt;/a&gt; among competing businesses with similar products and strategies. Furthermore, high employee engagement is not only good for an organization itself but also for employees as they can significantly benefit from it by achieving higher income and getting promotions ahead of others. In this article, we’ll cover six obvious benefits any business has from highly engaged workforce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/The-only-way-to-do-great-work-is-to-love-what-you-do.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The only way to do great work is to love what you do&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increased productivity&lt;/strong&gt;
It is a fact that the employees who are more enthusiastic about their job and who care about the company’s interests are more productive. Consequently, employees with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/nimblenews/blog/how-to-increase-productivity/&quot;&gt;higher productivity&lt;/a&gt; complete their duties sooner than the others, at the same time achieving better results. Often times they are motivated to go the extra mile to get the job done the right way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduced absenteeism and late arrivals&lt;/strong&gt;
Employees who are highly motivated and engaged with their job are eager to come at work because they feel good in the work environment. This significantly decreases the number of late arrivals and such staff members are less absent from work than some of their disengaged colleagues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increased satisfaction&lt;/strong&gt;
Highly engaged employees are more satisfied with their jobs, and as such, they may positively influence the whole working environment. Moreover, a positive attitude towards work and a willingness to go the extra mile to do the job the right way can have a positive impact on customer satisfaction as well. This is especially true when considering staff members working in direct relation with clients, such as customer support representatives, but the story doesn’t end there and often times extends to pretty much any role in the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved retention&lt;/strong&gt;
Finding the right employee for the job can be quite a challenging task. But when you do find one, your job is not done. Keeping your superstar employees in your company is as important as finding them in the first place. That’s why it’s important to know how to motivate employees. Working with staff members on their motivation and trying to boost their engagement can significantly influence the employee retention rate as well. Highly engaged employees are satisfied with their jobs; they have more opportunities to climb the career ladder and chances for leaving the company are much lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boosted profitability&lt;/strong&gt;
As a result of increased productivity, higher working morale and better work results, the profitability of the company can be significantly increased as well. By boosting your employee engagement, you can influence the profitability of your business and set your company on the path of success. Highly motivated and engaged employees reduce the operating costs, not only in the area of late arrivals and absenteeism, as mentioned before, but also in terms of an ethical approach when dealing with the company’s funds and expenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved communication&lt;/strong&gt;
Anyone who’s worked in a team knows how important it is to maintain a high level of morale and healthy communication in the work environment. Highly engaged employees, with their higher commitment and morale, significantly improve internal &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/nimblenews/product-news/tips-tricks/easy-and-effective-communication-tools/&quot;&gt;team communication&lt;/a&gt;, which results in better overall team results and a more positive work environment.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 12:27:47 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/the-impact-of-employee-engagement-on-business-performance/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/the-impact-of-employee-engagement-on-business-performance/</guid>
        
        <category>Employee Engagement</category>
        
        <category>Employee Retention</category>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Things Every Franchisee Should Know From the Start</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;its-going-to-take-more&quot;&gt;It’s Going to Take More&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep! That about covers it. Whatever you think it’s going to take you in terms of money, time, effort…take that and double it. Then you’ll have a conservative idea of what you’re up against when pursuing franchise opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more established and experienced the franchiser, the better the estimate they can give you on costs involved with starting a franchise. But remember, the franchiser may not be used to dealing with your local municipality, and every city has different requirements for businesses operating within their locale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to promoting, you’re going to want to pull out all the stops. Ask your friends and family to help you spread the word about your new business. Everywhere you go, look for new opportunities to spread the word about your venture. 
You’ll also likely be forgoing an income while you get started, and for the first months of operations. Starting a business requires 100% of your time and effort for an extended period of time, and you have to be “all in” if you want to hope to succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/3-Things-Every-Franchisee-Should-Know.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Work Schedule - Minimum Number of Hours&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;your-location-is-your-brand&quot;&gt;Your Location is Your Brand&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you sign up for a franchise, you’re purchasing the use of the franchiser’s brand and there is tremendous value in that. But you should be mindful that “your brand” is your location. You can be opening everyone’s favorite business and be exclusive to your area, but if people don’t have a good experience at your location, they won’t be back. Your brand is built with every customer, in every transaction. While the name you’re paying for from the  franchiser may get them in the door, they won’t come back if they don’t get an experience that’s consistent with their expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You invest heavily to purchase a franchise. You need to protect your investment. Win each customer’s business each time you interact with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;your-employees-are-your-brand-ambassadors&quot;&gt;Your Employees Are Your Brand Ambassadors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t be everywhere. In order to grow your business, you have to trust your employees to grow your business. They are the first people your customers meet. They are the first impression your customer has of your brand. Hire people you can trust and pay and treat them well. They are your front line in the battle to achieve customer service excellence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re going to buy into top franchises, just know what you’re in for. Plan for long hours and some sleepless nights. The costs and effort can be great, but so can the rewards of owning your own business.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 09:52:58 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/3-things-every-franchisee-should-know-from-the-start/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/3-things-every-franchisee-should-know-from-the-start/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Minimum Number of Hours per Week and Between Shifts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When being of charge of creating a work schedule for larger groups of employees, it is very important to stay on top of all kinds of scheduling rules and limitations for different staff members. Some staff members cannot work more than a certain number of hours per week, while others should not work less than a certain number of hours per week. On top of that, there could be a lot more requirements that need to be taken into consideration when creating an employees’ work schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With NimbleSchedule, you can easily set the following scheduling limits for each of your staff team members:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• The maximum number of hours per week
• The maximum number of hours per day
• The maximum number of work days per week
• The maximum number of shifts per day&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As from the last update, we’ve added two new options that were frequently requested by our clients. Those new options are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• The minimum number of hours per week
• The minimum number of hours between shifts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/Minimum-Number-of-Hours.jpg title=&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/Minimum-Number-of-Hours-thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Work Schedule - Minimum Number of Hours&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new scheduling limitations allow you to specify certain minimums that need to be taken into consideration when creating a work schedule and easily spot any issues ahead of time, when it’s not too late to correct things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;minimum-number-of-hours-per-week&quot;&gt;Minimum number of hours per week&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this new setting, you can easily set the minimum number of work hours for each of your employees and have such staff members clearly highlighted on the schedule page for cases when they’re not assigned with specified number of work hours for the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/Minimum-number-of-hours-per-week.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Work Schedule - Minimum number of hours per week&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through the schedule page, you’ll easily see which employees were not assigned with their minimum number of hours for the week and easily adjust the schedule for them. As you can see on the screenshot below, those employees that do not have the minimum number of work hours for the week will have an orange exclamation mark right below their name with the number of hours also highlighted in orange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;minimum-number-of-hours-between-shifts&quot;&gt;Minimum number of hours between shifts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through this new setting option you can specify the minimum hours between two shifts for your staff members. This is customizable for each employee, so you can easily tweak such a setting with different values for employees across different states or even different countries. Besides just specifying a specific number of hours between any two shifts, you can also tweak this setting to affect only shifts on consecutive days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/Minimum-number-of-hours-between-shifts.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Work Schedule - Minimum number of hours between shifts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although it appears as a minor tweak, this kind of setting can be very beneficial to companies of all sizes. For cases when you have employees working late evening shifts, you can now have the system show you a heads up pop-up window if someone tries to book that person for an early morning shift right after working a late night shift. Of course, there could be other scenarios as well where this kind of setting might be beneficial, especially with similar rules being implemented across different countries and states as a legal requirement across various industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our engineering team continues to work on adding more features and options to the system in order to make your scheduling and staff management process easier. If you have any questions or comments about these new options that we’ve recently added to the system, please do not hesitate to contact us and let us know your opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay Nimble!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 11:20:11 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/minimum-number-of-hours-per-week-and-between-shifts/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/minimum-number-of-hours-per-week-and-between-shifts/</guid>
        
        <category>Staff Management</category>
        
        
        <category>Product News</category>
        
        <category>Recent Releases</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NimbleSchedule Named as One of the Top 10 HR Cloud Solution Providers of 2016 by HR Tech Outlook</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Press-Release-Header_TEMP.png&quot; alt=&quot;Press Release Header_TEMP&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nimbleschedule-named-as-one-of-the-top-10-hr-cloud-solution-providers-of-2016-by-hr-tech-outlook&quot;&gt;NimbleSchedule Named as One of the Top 10 HR Cloud Solution Providers of 2016 by HR Tech Outlook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carlsbad, CA – May 25, 2016 -&lt;/strong&gt; Nimble Software Systems, Inc., DBA NimbleSchedule, a suite of cloud based workforce optimization applications, today announced it was named to the list of  “Top 10 Human Resources (HR) Cloud Solution Providers 2016,” by HR Tech Outlook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HR Tech Outlook selected NimbleSchedule as one of the Top 10 HR Cloud Solution Providers of 2016 based on the company’s specialties in workforce management solutions, includingemployee scheduling, human resource management, mobile human resource management, mobile employee scheduling and employee communication. NimbleSchedule is a simple and easy-to-use online employee scheduling software that frees up time for business owners and shift managers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“Attaining remarkable growth was indeed a tremendous achievement for NimbleSchedule,” said Hanna Wilson, editor-in-chief of HR Tech Outlook. “It’sour pleasure to honor Nimble Software Systems by naming NimbleSchedule in the list of Top 10 HR Cloud Solution Providers 2016.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“We are very pleased to receive this award from such a distinguished panel and top notch magazine,” said Sasha Poljak, CEO of Nimble Software Systems. “HR Tech Outlook’s recognition helps validate NimbleSchedule as an innovative cloud solution that meets the ever-changing demands of HR departments within organizations.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**About HR Tech Outlook **
Published from Fremont, California, HR Tech Outlook is a print magazine that talks about enterprise solutions that can redefine the business goals of tomorrow. A distinguished panel comprising of CEOs, CIOs, IT VPs including HR Tech Outlook’s editorial board, finalized the “Top 10 HR Cloud Solution Providers 2016” in the U.S. and shortlisted the best vendors and consultants. For more info: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hrtechoutlook.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.hrtechoutlook.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**About Nimble Software Systems **
NimbleSchedule is a brand of Nimble Software Systems, Inc. NimbleSchedule is an intuitive, web-based employee scheduling and time &amp;amp; attendance solution that helps companies streamline and automate their workforce operations. For more information about the company’s products, please visit: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nimbleschedule.com&quot;&gt;www.nimbleschedule.com&lt;/a&gt;. You may also connect with Nimble on Facebook (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/nimbleschedule&quot;&gt;facebook.com/nimbleschedule&lt;/a&gt;) and Twitter (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/nimbleschedule&quot;&gt;twitter.com/nimbleschedule&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 08:48:59 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/nimbleschedule-named-as-one-of-the-top-10/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/nimbleschedule-named-as-one-of-the-top-10/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Company News</category>
        
        <category>Press Release</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
